Binoy Michael Prakash

Santa Clara, CA, 95051 slashbin.in

+1-408-753-8127 linkedin.com/in/prakash-binov prakash.binoy@gmail.com github.com/binoymichael

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 9 years of combined experience in US healthcare payer, telecom and mobile banking domains and strong technical expertise in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Java, Android, SQL.

Currently pursuing Masters in Software Engineering at San Jose State University and am actively looking for summer 2017 internships.

SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, C++, Java

Others: Ruby on Rails, React, React Native, Android, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), Git, Shell Scripting

EXPERIENCE

MobME Wireless Solutions (http://mobme.in)

Senior Software Architect

Kochi, India

Jul 2011 - Jul 2016

- Spearheaded development of the backend API (Ruby on Rails) and mobile SDKs (Android & **JavaScript**) for JetSetPay, a mobile first payment gateway.
- Involved in the development of backend API/applications for Mobile-Express a **PKI infrastructure** based ecosystem. Mobile Express embeds users' digital signatures into their mobile crypto SIM cards, SD cards and can be used for authentication and document signing.
- Developed the prototype Android application and backend for Chillr (https://chillr.com), a P2P *money transfer* app. Chillr was later spun off to form a separate company.
- Involved in the development of a *Ruby* framework for creating USSD applications and led a team of 5 engineers to rebuild entire suite of USSD applications. The framework was later open-sourced (colloquy) and some of my contributions can be viewed here.

Cognizant Technology Solutions

Chennai, India

Associate (Systems Analyst/Programmer for Anthem Inc. projects)

Nov 2006 – Dec 2010

- Created functional specifications/designs for *Trizetto Facets* applications. Coordinated with clients, developer teams, vendors and led implementation of these projects.
- Designed and developed numerous Trizetto Facets based applications using Java, Sybase(ASE), Shell scripts and SQL
- Involved in performance tuning activities to enhance scalability of client systems.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Outodo an outliner created using JavaScript/jQuery that I use to maintain my personal lists.
- FPL Mini League Viewer a chrome extension to view fantasy football mini league details.

EDUCATION

Masters in Software Engineering (2016 - Present) from San Jose State University, California, USA. Post Graduate Certificate in IT Management. (2014 - 2015) from IIM, Kozhikode. India. B. Tech in Applied Electronics, (2002 - 2006) from College of Engineering, Trivandrum. India.